Finding Aid for Floyd Josiah Miller papers, 1907-1954
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Floyd Josiah Miller papers 1907-1954
Miller, Floyd Josiah, 1886-1954.
2 linear feet and 4 oversize volumes
851925 Aa 2; AC
Editor and publisher of the Daily Tribune; scrapbooks of newspaper columns and editorials, personal scrapbooks, diary, and miscellaneous.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Richard P. Miller (donor no. 5168 ).
The collection is open to research.
Floyd Josiah Miller was editor and publisher of the Daily Tribune, a south Oakland County, Michigan, newspaper.
The collection is comprised of four series: Biographical; Newspaper career; Miscellaneous; and Scrapbooks. The Biographical series is important for Miller's diary of his life and career in the period of 1932-1954. The diary provides a detailed description of the operation of the newspaper during the depression with comments on state and national politics. The Newspaper career series includes scrapbooks of his editorials and his "Personally Speaking" column. The Scrapbook series includes clippings, programs, scattered photographs, and memorabilia from his career and personal activities.
Subjects:
The daily tribune (Royal Oak, Mich.); Depressions--1929--Michigan.; Journalists--Michigan--Royal Oak.; Michigan--Politics and government--1929-1938.; Newspaper publishing--Michigan--Royal Oak.; Oakland County (Mich.); Newspaper editors--Michigan--Royal Oak.; Royal Oak (Mich.); Royal Oak daily tribune; Michigan--Politics and government--1837-1950.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Scrapbooks.
- Biographical
  - Autobiography of early career, with biographical and family material (Box 1)
  - Diary, 1932-1954 (Box 1)
- Newspaper career
  - Newspaper column, "Personally Speaking"
    - 1929-1937, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - September 1937-January 1940, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - January 1940-October 1943, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - October 1943-October 1944, 1 volume (Box 1)
    - 1952-1954, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Local editorials
    (include some written by Philip F. Miller)
    - 1946-1949 (Box 2)
    - 1950-1951 (Box 2)
    - 1952 (Box 2)
    - 1953 (Box 2)
    - 1954 (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence, 1907-1918 and undated (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous cards and selective service materials (Box 2)
  - Copies of Indianapolis Spectator, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Pamphlet: "Land of the Incas" (Box 2)
    (Reprinted from "Personally Speaking" articles)
- Personal Scrapbooks, 1932-1947
  - 1932-1937 (Volume 1)
  - 1937-1941 (Volume 2)
  - 1941-1947 (Volume 3)
  - June-September 1938 (Volume 4)
Related Materials
The library also houses the papers of Floyd Miller's son Philip F. Miller and his grandson Richard P. Miller.